[
	{
		"id": "css-1",
		"question": "Which of the following is an example of a general descendant selector?",
		"correct_answer": "ul li",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"h1, h2",
			"input[type=\"text\"]",
			"div &gt; p"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-2",
		"question": "Which one of the following CSS functions allows you to change the shape of an element by warping its points by the specified angle in each direction?",
		"correct_answer": "skew()",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"translate()",
			"warp()",
			"rotate()"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-3",
		"question": "Which selector is used to find anchor elements that have not been visited by the user?",
		"correct_answer": "a:link",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"a:active",
			"a:hover",
			"a:visited"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-4",
		"question": "Which attribute allows you to use a media query on a <link> element to conditionally load an external stylesheet?",
		"correct_answer": "media",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"href",
			"rel",
			"type"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-5",
		"question": "The vertical-align property sets the vertical alignment for which of the following?",
		"correct_answer": "Table cells and inline elements",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"All text-based elements",
			"Block elements and tables",
			"&lt;span&gt; and &lt;p&gt; inner text"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-7",
		"question": "<p>What is the result of the CSS rules below?</p> <div class=\"code\"><p>.container p {</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;float: left!important;</p><p>}</p></div> <div class=\"code\"><p>&lt;div class=\"container\"&gt;</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&lt;p&gt;This is a paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&lt;p&gt;This is another paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;/div&gt;</p></div>",
		"correct_answer": "The &lt;div class=\"container\"&gt; default height value will be 0 as all child elements are floated.",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"The children elements float attribute value is also left.",
			"The overflow attribute value of &lt;div class=\"container\"&gt; is \"auto\" by default.",
			"The &lt;div class=\"container\"&gt; margin attribute value is ignored."
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-8",
		"question": "Which statement is true regarding the animation of SVG elements with CSS?",
		"correct_answer": "They can be animated with the same CSS properties as HTML elements.",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"CSS property animations for SVG only work in the Chrome Web Browser",
			"It is not possible to animate SVG elements with CSS.",
			"SVG elements have a special set of CSS animation properties."
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-9",
		"question": "<p>Based on the structure below, which selector type will target only &lt;p&gt; elements that immediately follow after a given &lt;div&gt; element?</p><div class=\"code\"><p>&lt;body&gt;</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&lt;div&gt;</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&lt;p&gt;Example paragraph.&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&lt;/div&gt;</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&lt;p&gt;Which selector will target only this paragraph?&lt;/p&gt;</p><p>&lt;/body&gt;</p></div>",
		"correct_answer": "An adjacent sibling selector",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"A general sibling selector",
			"A descendant selector",
			"A child selector"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-10",
		"question": "<p>Based on the following CSS and HTML, what will be the final color value of the &lt;li&gt; elements?</p><div class=\"code\"><p>&lt;style&gt;</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;.list li { color: red; }</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;div ul li { color: blue; }</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;li { color: green; }</p><p>&lt;/style&gt;</p><p>&lt;div class=\"list\"&gt;</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&lt;ul&gt;</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&lt;li&gt;Item 1&lt;/li&gt;</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&lt;li&gt;Item 2&lt;/li&gt;</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&nbsp;&lt;li&gt;Item 3&lt;/li&gt;</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&lt;/ul&gt;</p><p>&lt;/div&gt;</p></div>",
		"correct_answer": "Red",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Blue",
			"Black",
			"Green"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-12",
		"question": "<p>If the following selectors are being applied to the same element, what will be the final color of the element?</p> <div class=\"code\"><p>.element {</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;color: red;</p><p>}</p><p></p><p>div[id=\"container\"] h1 {</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;color: blue;</p><p>}</p><p></p><p>.main div:nth-of-type(2) h1 {</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;color: green;</p><p>}</p></div>",
		"correct_answer": "Green",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Red",
			"Black",
			"Blue"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-13",
		"question": "Which of the following properties has a default value of ease and specifies how the speed during a transition will be calculated?",
		"correct_answer": "transition-timing-function",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"transition-duration",
			"transition-property",
			"transition-delay"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-14",
		"question": "Which value of the display property will change the layout behavior of an element to act like a block element in the flexbox model?",
		"correct_answer": "flex",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"block-flex",
			"flexbox",
			"inline-flex"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-15",
		"question": "<p>What will be the final color value of the span below?</p><div class=\"code\"><p>&lt;div&gt; </p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;&lt;p&gt;This is a &lt;span&gt;paragraph&lt;/span&gt;.&lt;/p&gt; </p><p>&lt;/div&gt; </p></div><p></p><div class=\"code\"><p>div span { </p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;color: blue; </p><p>} </p><p></p><p>p span {</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;color: green;</p><p>}</p><p></p><p>span { </p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;color: red; </p><p>}</p></div>",
		"correct_answer": "Green",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Blue",
			"Black",
			"Red"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-16",
		"question": "Which of the following is true of an element that precedes a floated element?",
		"correct_answer": "The element will not be affected by the floated element.",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"The element will float to the left of the next element in document flow.",
			"The element will float to the right of the next element in document flow.",
			"The element will flow around the following element."
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-17",
		"question": "<p>Which of the following best describes the result of the Cascading Style Sheets (CSS) rule below?</p><div class=\"code\"><p>.element {</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;left: 20px;</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;top: 50px;</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;z-index: 3;</p><p>}</p></div><p></p><div class=\"code\"><p>&lt;div class=\"element\"&gt;Some text&lt;/div&gt;</p></div>",
		"correct_answer": "None of the declarations will have an effect unless a position property is set to anything other than static or sticky.  ",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"The element will have a z-index of 3 but top and left properties will be ignored.",
			"The element will be offset 20 pixels to the left and 50 pixels from the top of the browser window, with a stacking order of 3 on the z axis.",
			"The element will be offset by its original position left by 20 pixels and 50px from the top, and the z-index value will be ignored."
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-18",
		"question": "<p>What is the effect of using a negative number in a padding declaration? Example:</p><div class=\"code\"><p>p {</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;padding-top: -10px;</p><p>}</p></div>",
		"correct_answer": "Same as padding-top: 0px;",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Same as margin-top: -10px;",
			"Same as position: absolute; top: -10px;",
			"Same as padding-top: 10px;"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-19",
		"question": "What is a valid value for the font-stretch attribute?",
		"correct_answer": "normal",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"stretch",
			"narrow",
			"justify"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-20",
		"question": "Which list-style-type property renders a filled circle?",
		"correct_answer": "disc",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"circle",
			"roman",
			"square"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-21",
		"question": "Which of the following properties allows you to use a customized cursor?",
		"correct_answer": "cursor",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"cursor-style-type",
			"cursor-style",
			"style"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-22",
		"question": "<p>On which side will there be a 30px padding given the following declaration? </p><div class=\"code\"><p>padding: 10px 15px 20px 30px;</p></div>",
		"correct_answer": "Left",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Bottom",
			"Right",
			"Top"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-23",
		"question": "<p>Which of the following would be the result of the rule below?</p><div class=\"code\"><p>tr:nth-child(2n){</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;background-color: red; </p><p>}</p></div>",
		"correct_answer": "Changes the background color of every even table row to red",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Changes the text color of ONLY the second row in a table to red",
			"Changes the text color of every even number table row to red",
			"Changes the background color of ONLY the second row in a table to red"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-24",
		"question": "What does the background-attachment property do?",
		"correct_answer": "It sets whether a background image should scroll with the content, or be fixed.",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"It displays a link to the background.",
			"It links background as an external file.",
			"It attaches an image to the background."
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-25",
		"question": "Which of the following styles has the lowest specificity?",
		"correct_answer": "*",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"h1",
			"#element",
			"&lt;h1 style=\"color: red\"&gt;&lt;/h1&gt;"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-26",
		"question": "Which of the following keywords can be used to force property inheritance on an element?",
		"correct_answer": "Inherit",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Initial",
			"Parent",
			"!important"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-27",
		"question": "Which of the following is a valid pseudo-element?",
		"correct_answer": "::after",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			":last-child",
			":first-of-type",
			":active"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-28",
		"question": "<p>Which element will be matched by the following CSS selector?</p><div class=\"code\"><p>div[class^=\"foo\"]</p></div>",
		"correct_answer": "<div class=\"codeAnswer\">&lt;div class=\"foobar\"&gt; ... &lt;/div&gt;</div>",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"<div class=\"codeAnswer\">&lt;div class=\"^foo\"&gt; ... &lt;/div&gt;</div>",
			"<div class=\"codeAnswer\">&lt;div class=\"baz-foo\"&gt; ... &lt;/div&gt;</div>",
			"<div class=\"codeAnswer\">&lt;div class=\"~foo\"&gt; ... &lt;/div&gt; </div>"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-30",
		"question": "What is the default value of the float property?",
		"correct_answer": "none",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"flex",
			"inherit",
			"unset"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
    {
		"id": "css-31",
		"question": "Which of the following will redefine the default margin and padding settings for all browsers so that they are identical?",
		"correct_answer": "Setting margin and padding to 0",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Setting margin and padding to auto",
			"Setting margin and padding to inherit",
			"Setting margin and padding to custom"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-32",
		"question": "With regards to the cascade effect of CSS, when does the order of the rules take precedence?",
		"correct_answer": "The order matters when the elements possess equal specificity.",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"The order matters only when !important is NOT used.",
			"The order only matters when using external style sheets.",
			"The order has no effect on styles."
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-33",
		"question": "What is the transform: translate() method used for?",
		"correct_answer": "To offset elements from their current position",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"To translate text to the language given as a parameter",
			"To use non-euclidean geometry on elements",
			"To skew an element's bounding box"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-34",
		"question": "Which of the following declarations could be used to hide an image without affecting the document's layout?",
		"correct_answer": "visibility: hidden;",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"display: hide;",
			"visibility: invisible;",
			"display: none;"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-35",
		"question": "Which of the following best describes the role of the float property?",
		"correct_answer": "To change the default behavior of an element in normal document flow relative to its containing block",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"To alter the default behavior and type of an element's rendering box",
			"To position an element relative to its original position by the specified offsets",
			"To change the layout model used by an element"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
		{
		"id": "css-36",
		"question": "Which is a layout model that demonstrates the relationship between parts in an element's rendering box (e.g. margins, padding, borders)?",
		"correct_answer": "Box model",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Flex-box",
			"Table model",
			"Border-box"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-38",
		"question": "Which fragment identifier correctly implements a pseudo-class target to style a URL?",
		"correct_answer": "#home:target",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			":target #home",
			"#home[target]",
			":target(#home)"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-39",
		"question": "Which property will set the value of an inline element's alignment?",
		"correct_answer": "float",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"direction",
			"display",
			"position"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-40",
		"question": "<p>Which option is true regarding the @keyframes rule below?</p><div class=\"code\"><p>@keyframes example {</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;0% { left: 0 ; }</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;50% { left: 20px; top: 50px; }</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;50% { left: 10px !important; }</p><p>&nbsp;&nbsp;100% { left: 0 ; top: 0 ; }</p><p>}</p></div>",
		"correct_answer": "The declaration left: 10px !important will not be applied because !important declarations are ignored in @keyframe rules.",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"The 50% { left: 10px !important; } attributes will be applied because of the !important declaration.",
			"!important is an illegal declaration with @keyframe causing the last rule, 100% { left: 0; top: 0; }, to be ignored.",
			"50% { left: 10px !important; } will be ignored because of the duplicate keyframe definition."
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-41",
		"question": "Intermediate values used during a transition are calculated using which attribute?",
		"correct_answer": "transition-timing-function",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"transition-duration-time",
			"transition-duration",
			"transition-time"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-42",
		"question": "What object-fit attribute value sets a video or image to maintain its aspect ratio while fitting within the parent content box?",
		"correct_answer": "Contain",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Fill",
			"Cover",
			"Repeat"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-43",
		"question": "Which style attribute value is used to set the image of a list item?",
		"correct_answer": "list-style-image",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"li-image-style",
			"list-image",
			"li-image-url"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-44",
		"question": "Which property can be used to control the formatting of white space inside of an element?",
		"correct_answer": "White-space",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Tracking",
			"Text-space",
			"Text-wrap"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-45",
		"question": "Which of the following is the correct syntax for a media query that will be applied to all devices with an orientation of landscape and a minimum width of 600px?",
		"correct_answer": "<p>@media (min-width: 600px) and (orientation: landscape) {</p><p></p><p>}</p>",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"<p>@media (landscape) and (min-width: 600px) {</p><p></p><p>}</p>",
			"<p>@media print and (orientation: landscape) and (min-width:600px) {</p><p></p><p>}</p>",
			"<p>@media (device-mode: landscape, min-width: 600px) {</p><p></p><p>}</p>"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-46",
		"question": "Which of the following is an example of a non-inherited property in CSS?",
		"correct_answer": "Padding",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Color",
			"Font-family",
			"Text-align"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-47",
		"question": "Assuming an element has a border applied, where are margins located according to the CSS box model?",
		"correct_answer": "Immediately outside of an element's border",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Between an element's padding and border",
			"Immediately outside of an element's content box",
			"Between an element's border and outline"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-48",
		"question": "What is the default display value of a &lt;button&gt; tag?",
		"correct_answer": "Inline-block",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"Block",
			"Visible",
			"Inline-grid"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-49",
		"question": "Which option is true about inline styles if the keyword !important is NOT added to the style value?",
		"correct_answer": "They will override a style defined inside the &lt;head&gt; tag, in an external style sheet, or in a browser.",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"They will be overridden by a browser default value.",
			"They will be overridden by a style defined inside the &lt;head&gt; tag.",
			"They will be overridden by an external style sheet."
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-50",
		"question": "Which option best describes the purpose of the @keyframes at-rule?",
		"correct_answer": "To control the intermediate steps in a CSS animation sequence",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"To set FPS (Frames Per Second) of HTML5 Canvas animations",
			"To control timing for WebGL animations",
			"To create custom timing functions for CSS animations"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-52",
		"question": "Which of the following declarations can be used in CSS to cause adjacent table cells to share borders?",
		"correct_answer": "border-collapse: collapse;",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"border: share;",
			"table: share-border;",
			"tableborder: collapse;"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-53",
		"question": "Which of the following properties specifies the type of list-item marker?",
		"correct_answer": "list-style-type",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"list-style-all",
			"list-marker",
			"list-style-marker"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-54",
		"question": "What is the purpose of the line-height attribute?",
		"correct_answer": "Sets the distance between lines",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"To vertically align text in an HTML element",
			"To create synthetically condensed fonts by setting text height",
			"To set the height of the inner text"
		],
		"source": ""
	},
	{
		"id": "css-55",
		"question": "Which of the following is true of using @import to load an external stylesheet?",
		"correct_answer": "@import will be ignored if it is not the first rule in a stylesheet, with the exception of @charset rules",
		"incorrect_answers": [
			"@import must be placed last in a stylesheet or it will be ignored",
			"@import statements can include at most one media query",
			"@import should be used sparingly due to poor browser support"
		],
		"source": ""
	}
]